<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">

<channel>
      <title> in consequently.org: Greg Restall’s website </title>
	  <itunes:subtitle>Greg Restall's publications on logic and philosophy</itunes:subtitle>
	  <itunes:author>Greg Restall</itunes:author>
	  <itunes:owner>
	  <itunes:name>Greg Restall</itunes:name>
	  <itunes:email>greg@consequently.org</itunes:email>
	  </itunes:owner>
	  <itunes:category text="Education">
	  <itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
	  </itunes:category>
	  <itunes:keywords>Philosophy, Logic, mathematics, pdf, research, University, Greg Restall, Melbourne, Australia, Victoria</itunes:keywords>
	  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	  <itunes:image href="http://consequently.org/img/avatar2.jpg" />
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://consequently.org/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 11:58:11 AEST</updated>


<item>
<title>PHIL20030: Meaning, Possibility and Paradox</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL20030/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL20030/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PHIL20030&lt;/span&gt;: Meaning, Possibility and Paradox&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate subject. The idea that the meaning of a sentence depends on the meanings of its parts is fundamental to the way we understand logic, language and the mind. In this subject, we look at the different ways that this idea has been applied in logic throughout the 20th Century and into the present day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the subject, our focus is on the concepts of necessity and possibility, and the way that &amp;lsquo;possible worlds semantics&amp;rsquo; has been used in theories of meaning. We will focus on the logic of necessity and possibility (modal logic), times (temporal logic), conditionality and dependence (counterfactuals), and the notions of analyticity and a priority so important to much of philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the subject, we examine closely the assumption that every statement we make is either true or false but not both. We will examine the paradoxes of truth (like the so-called &amp;lsquo;liar paradox&amp;rsquo;) and vagueness (the ‘sorites paradox&amp;rsquo;), and we will investigate different ways attempts at resolving these paradoxes by going beyond our traditional views of truth (using &amp;lsquo;many valued logics&amp;rsquo;) or by defending the traditional perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject serves as an introduction to ways that logic is applied in the study of language, epistemology and metaphysics, so it is useful to those who already know some philosophy and would like to see how logic relates to those issues. It is also useful to those who already know some logic and would like to learn new logical techniques and see how these techniques can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject is offered to University of Melbourne undergraduate students (for Arts students as a part of the Philosophy major, for non-Arts students, as a breadth subject). Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2015/PHIL20030&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make use of video lectures I have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2470375&#34;&gt;freely available on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in this sort of thing, I commend them to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL40013: Uncertainty, Vagueness and Disagreement</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL40013/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL40013/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PHIL40013&lt;/span&gt;: Uncertainty, Vagueness and Paradox&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; honours seminar subject for fourth-year students. Our aim in the Honours program is to introduce students to current work in research in Philosophy. In 2015, I will cover some topic introducing logic and its applications to issues in metaphysics, epistemology or philosophy of language. For further information, contact me. To participate, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2015/PHIL40013&#34;&gt;the handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Dubrovnik Workshop on Pluralisms</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/pluralism-dubrovnik/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/pluralism-dubrovnik/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m giving a presentation on logical pluralism at the 2015 Ohio State University/Dubrovnik workshop on Pluralism in Mathematics, Logic and Semantics, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iuc.hr/&#34;&gt;Inter University Center&lt;/a&gt;, Dubrovnik, Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Workshop on Verbal Disputes and their Philosophical Significance</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/verbal-disputes-oxford/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/verbal-disputes-oxford/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m giving a presentation on proof theory, modality, existence and verbal disputes at a workshop held at the University of Oxford in May, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Assertion, Denial, Accepting, Rejecting, Symmetry and Paradox</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/assertiondenialparadox/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/assertiondenialparadox/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Proponents of a dialethic or &amp;ldquo;truth-value glut&amp;rdquo; response to the paradoxes of self-reference argue that &amp;ldquo;truth-value gap&amp;rdquo; analyses of the paradoxes fall foul of the extended liar paradox: &amp;ldquo;this sentence is not true.&amp;rdquo; If we pay attention to the role of assertion and denial and the behaviour of negation in both &amp;ldquo;gap&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;glut&amp;rdquo; analyses, we see that the situation with these approaches has a pleasing symmetry: gap approaches take some denials to not be expressible by negation, and glut approaches take some negations to not express denials. But in the light of this symmetry, considerations against a gap view point to parallel considerations against a glut view. Those who find some reason to prefer one view over another (and this is almost everyone) must find some reason to break this symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short paper was written for presentation at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philosophy.unimelb.edu.au/aap2004&#34;&gt;AAP2004&lt;/a&gt;. After very many revisions, it&amp;rsquo;s finally going to be published in an edited collection from members and friends of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/arche/projects/logic/&#34;&gt;Arché project on Foundations of Logical Consequence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>[Title to be confirmed]</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/ctc-seminar/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/ctc-seminar/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m giving a research seminar on May 1 at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctc.edu.au/&#34;&gt;Catholic Theological College&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Logic: Language and Information 2</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic2_coursera/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic2_coursera/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jen Davoren and I are running &lt;em&gt;Logic: Language and Information 2&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; again in 2015. You can enrol &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/logic2&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This course follows on from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/logic1&#34;&gt;Logic: Language and Information 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Another View of the Old Quad</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/another-view-of-the-old-quad/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:23:10 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/another-view-of-the-old-quad/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another view of my building at work, in the autumn light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/05L-ksFQ4j/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Old Quad, back entrance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Greg Restall (@consequently) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-03-31T13:20:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 31, 2015 at 6:20am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s around the corner from the shot I took &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2015/back-in-the-office/&#34;&gt;a couple of months ago&lt;/a&gt;. If you go between the two trees in the middle of the picture and turn left, you can enter the Old Quad’s hidden back staircase, and make your way to my office.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Incarnation and Detachment: Philosophy, Prayer, and Taking Positions</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/csn-incarnation-and-detachment/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/csn-incarnation-and-detachment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m giving a talk entitled “Incarnation and Detachment: Philosophy, Prayer, and Taking Positions” at the first 2015 meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://christianscholarsnetwork.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;Christian Scholars Network&lt;/a&gt;. (We&amp;rsquo;ll meet at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedan.com.au&#34;&gt;Dan O&amp;rsquo;Connell Pub&lt;/a&gt; at 7pm on Tuesday March 24. Come early to share dinner before the talk and discussion.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the talk I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss some of the parallels between the range of cognitive attitudes to be found in reasoning and philosophical reflection on the one hand, and prayer, on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://christianscholarsnetwork.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;Christian Scholars Network&lt;/a&gt; is a ministry of &lt;a href=&#34;http://sjoc.org.au&#34;&gt;St. James Old Cathedral&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone who is interested in the intersection of faith and intellect is entirely welcome to participate. It&amp;rsquo;s coordinated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sjoc.org.au/people/staff&#34;&gt;Rev.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://corner.acu.edu.au/research_supervision/framework/browse.php?srperid=2260&#34;&gt;Dr. Jeffrey Hanson&lt;/a&gt;.  For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://christianscholarsnetwork.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;the Network&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Advocacy on Sydney Road</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/advocacy-on-sydney-road/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 12:49:30 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/advocacy-on-sydney-road/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On the afternoon of Sunday March 1, Sydney Road in Brunswick was transformed by its annual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brunswickmusicfestival.com.au/sydney-road-street-party.htm&#34;&gt;Street Party&lt;/a&gt;. Over four blocks of this busy inner north thoroughfare was closed to trams and cars, lined by stalls, punctuated with live bands, and filled with crowds. Everyone was sampling wares, eating, drinking and soaking in the atmosphere. It&amp;rsquo;s a distinctive slice of multicultural Brunswick life, and an opportunity for everyone to get out and sample that Brunswick experience in all its variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/SRSP-bands.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Live music at the Sydney Road Street Party&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Live music at the Sydney Road Street Party&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four of us from the Melbourne Inner North &lt;a href=&#34;http://tear.org.au&#34;&gt;TEAR&lt;/a&gt; Group were there, between a Scout Group sausage sizzle on the one side and the Animal Protection Society, with its vegan cookbooks and petitions on the other. We ran a little stall lined with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tear.org.au/learn/target/&#34;&gt;TEAR Targets&lt;/a&gt;, information about Australian Aid and its positive impact on poverty and development in our region, and postcards to send to the Foreign Minister, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juliebishop.com.au&#34;&gt;Julie Bishop&lt;/a&gt;. We were encouraging our fellow residents of the Inner North to urge Julie Bishop and our government to our commitments towards meeting the Millennium Development Goals. In honour of International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, we made flowers for passers by to attach to their postcard, and we collected nearly 50 to send along to Canberra to help the government to get the message that our community takes helping our neighbours to be an important part of our national character, and not something to be dropped when some difficult decisions need to be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/SRSP-Postcards.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Signed Postcards with Flowers for Julie Bishop&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Signed Postcards with Flowers for Julie Bishop&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the afternoon we had many interesting conversations with passers by, young and old, including local politicians from the Greens and the ALP, many students, local Brunswick residents and visitors from further afield, and a couple of anarchists up from Tasmania&amp;mdash;who agreed with our aims but thought that our methods were far too conservative. All our conversations were friendly, whether passers by agreed with us or disagreed, and many were happy to see a Christian organisation like &lt;a href=&#34;http://tear.org.au&#34;&gt;TEAR&lt;/a&gt; with a presence on the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most likely, 50 signatures on petitions is not enough on its own to change a Minister&amp;rsquo;s mind—even if the flowers everyone attached were very attractive—but this was one small part of an ongoing community conversation. May that conversation continue, and may the wider community find its voice so that we all recognise what it means to be a good neighbour to those around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/SRSP-stall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TEAR Stall at the Sydney Road Street Party&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;TEAR Stall at the Sydney Road Street Party&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry was originally published at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tear.org.au/news/sydney-road-street-festival&#34;&gt;TEAR News&lt;/a&gt;. Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tear.org.au/act/tear-groups&#34;&gt;TEAR site&lt;/a&gt; for more information about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tear.org.au/act/tear-groups&#34;&gt;TEAR Groups near you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Our Thinking Behind Logic Teaching on Coursera</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/our-thinking-behind-logic-teaching-on-coursera/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 14:46:22 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/our-thinking-behind-logic-teaching-on-coursera/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Just today, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/102098742&#34;&gt;a video of an interview with me from 2013&lt;/a&gt;, explaining our thinking behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic1_coursera/&#34;&gt;teaching introductory logic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic2_coursera/&#34;&gt;on Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, and the connections between this and &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/UNIB10002&#34;&gt;classroom teaching&lt;/a&gt;. Come for the ideas, stay for the crazy hand gestures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/102098742&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Come and work with me on proof theory and philosophy</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/come-work-with-me/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 12:28:44 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/come-work-with-me/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; announce that I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/caw/en/job/885576/postdoctoral-fellow-philosophy&#34;&gt;job to offer&lt;/a&gt; on my five year ARC funded research project in philosophical logic and its applications, &amp;ldquo;Meaning in Action: new techniques for language, logic and information.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a two year postdoctoral research position, with a little bit of teaching on the side. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in philosophical logic, and would like to join the logic group at Melbourne, this is the job for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details are &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/caw/en/job/885576/postdoctoral-fellow-philosophy&#34;&gt;online at the University of Melbourne careers site&lt;/a&gt;, and if you  applying, you should read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/misc/DP150103801_app.pdf&#34;&gt;project description&lt;/a&gt; so you can address how you would contribute to the research project in your application for the job. To apply, follow the instructions &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/caw/en/job/885576/postdoctoral-fellow-philosophy&#34;&gt;on the University of Melbourne careers site&lt;/a&gt;. The closing date for the application is &lt;strong&gt;April 19, 2015&lt;/strong&gt; (That&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Melbourne&lt;/em&gt; time. Don&amp;rsquo;t be bitten by thinking that midnight April 19 &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; time is still April 19 &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; time.) If you have any questions, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get back to me. And let everyone know about this position. I&amp;rsquo;ll be delighted to have a strong field of applicants. This is an exciting research project, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to working on it with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Here are a few answers to questions I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no fixed starting date for the position, though if you can be on board for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unimelb.edu.au/unisec/PDates/acadcale.html&#34;&gt;Semester 2, 2015&lt;/a&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s a strong plus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teaching responsibilities for the position are small (at most &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of the workload), and are to be decided in consultation with me&amp;mdash;this part of the role is to give the candidate some teaching experience, and to cover a little of my teaching to free me up to do some more research. Take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/&#34;&gt;my teaching&lt;/a&gt; over the last few years, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get an idea of the opportunities for teaching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have other questions about the position, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;#about&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;, and if you know some likely candidates, please point them this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>UNIB10002: Logic, Language and Information</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/UNIB10002/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/UNIB10002/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UNIB10002&lt;/span&gt;: Logic, Language and Information&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate breadth subject, introducing logic and its applications to students from a broad range of disciplines in the Arts, Sciences and Engineering. I coordinate this subject with my colleague Dr. Jen Davoren, with help from Dr. Lesley Stirling and Dr. Peter Schachte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject is taught to University of Melbourne undergraduate students. Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2014/UNIB10002&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We teach this in a &amp;lsquo;flipped classroom&amp;rsquo; model, using resources from our Coursera subjects &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic1_coursera&#34;&gt;Logic 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic2_coursera&#34;&gt;Logic 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL30043: The Power and Limits of Logic</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL30043/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL30043/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PHIL30043&lt;/span&gt;: The Power and Limits of Logic&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2015/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne undergraduate subject&lt;/a&gt;. It covers the metatheory of classical first order predicate logic, beginning at the &lt;em&gt;Soundness&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Completeness&lt;/em&gt; Theorems (proved not once but &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt;, first for a tableaux proof system for predicate logic, then a Hilbert proof system), through the &lt;em&gt;Deduction Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Compactness&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cantor&amp;rsquo;s Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Downward L&amp;ouml;wenheim&amp;ndash;Skolem Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Recursive Functions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Register Machines&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Representability&lt;/em&gt; and ending up at &lt;em&gt;G&amp;ouml;del&amp;rsquo;s Incompleteness Theorems&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;L&amp;ouml;b&amp;rsquo;s Theorem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/godel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kurt Godel, seated&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Kurt Gödel, seated&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject is taught to University of Melbourne undergraduate students (for Arts students as a part of the Philosophy major, for non-Arts students, as a breadth subject). Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2015/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I make use of video lectures I have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409&#34;&gt;freely available on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/handouts/Subject-Guide-PHIL30043-in-2015.pdf&#34;&gt;course guide&lt;/a&gt; (303KB PDF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outline:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Outline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is divided into four major sections and a short prelude. Here is a list of all of the videos, in case you&amp;rsquo;d like to follow along with the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;prelude:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Prelude&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59401942&#34;&gt;Logical Equivalence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59403292&#34;&gt;Disjunctive Normal Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59403535&#34;&gt;Why DNF Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59463569&#34;&gt;Prenex Normal Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59466141&#34;&gt;Models for Predicate Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59880539&#34;&gt;Trees for Predicate Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;completeness:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Completeness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/59883806&#34;&gt;Introducing Soundness and Completeness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/60249309&#34;&gt;Soundness for Tree Proofs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/60250515&#34;&gt;Completeness for Tree Proofs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/61677028&#34;&gt;Hilbert Proofs for Propositional Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/61685762&#34;&gt;Conditional Proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/62221512&#34;&gt;Hilbert Proofs for Predicate Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/103720089&#34;&gt;Theories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/103757399&#34;&gt;Soundness and Completeness for Hilbert Proofs for Predicate Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;compactness:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Compactness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63454250&#34;&gt;Counting Sets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63454732&#34;&gt;Diagonalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63454732&#34;&gt;Compactness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63455121&#34;&gt;Non-Standard Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63462354&#34;&gt;Inexpressibility of Finitude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/63462519&#34;&gt;Downward L&amp;ouml;wenheim&amp;ndash;Skolem Theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;computability:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Computability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/64162062&#34;&gt;Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/64167354&#34;&gt;Register Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/64207986&#34;&gt;Recursive Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/64435763&#34;&gt;Register Machine computable functions are Recursive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/64604717&#34;&gt;The Uncomputable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;undecidability-and-incompleteness:76294f5d7786e9873ad8b21b9edd2475&#34;&gt;Undecidability and Incompleteness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65382456&#34;&gt;Deductively Defined Theories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65392670&#34;&gt;The Finite Model Property&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65393543&#34;&gt;Completeness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65440901&#34;&gt;Introducing Robinson&amp;rsquo;s Arithmetic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65442289&#34;&gt;Induction and Peano Arithmetic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65443650&#34;&gt;Representing Functions and Sets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65483655&#34;&gt;G&amp;ouml;del Numbering and Diagonalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65497886&#34;&gt;Q (and any consistent extension of Q) is undecidable, and incomplete if it&amp;rsquo;s deductively defined&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65498016&#34;&gt;First Order Predicate Logic is Undecidable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65501745&#34;&gt;True Arithmetic is not Deductively Defined&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409/video/65505372&#34;&gt;If Con(PA) then PA doesn&amp;rsquo;t prove Con(PA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Academic Genealogy</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/academic-genealogy/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:35:19 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/academic-genealogy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have known about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/index.php&#34;&gt;Mathematical Genealogy Project&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2004/06/07/ancestors/&#34;&gt;quite some time&lt;/a&gt;, but, prompted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucalgary.ca/rzach/blog/2015/02/academic-genealogy-graphed.html&#34;&gt;Richard Zach&lt;/a&gt; I notice two new and wonderful things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidalber.net/&#34;&gt;David Alber&lt;/a&gt; has produced in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidalber.net/geneagrapher/&#34;&gt;Geneagrapher&lt;/a&gt; a neat tool to download genealogy data and save a .dot file, which can be read by &lt;a href=&#34;http://graphviz.org&#34;&gt;Graphviz&lt;/a&gt; and displayed as a directed graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a detail from my genealogy. (This image is a link to a pdf file of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/images/restall-genealogy.pdf&#34;&gt;entire thing&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/images/restall-genealogy.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/genealogy-detail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Greg Restall&#39;s Academic Genealogy&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Some of my genealogy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second new thing is that I found to my great surprise and delight that the database has been &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; filled out since I last looked through it. My academic ancestry has been traced back to the 14th Century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/images/restall-genealogy.pdf&#34;&gt;graph&lt;/a&gt;, you can see that there is a recent branch point at my great&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-grandparent, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=17975&#34;&gt;Richard Rado&lt;/a&gt;, who had two supervisors, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=17806&#34;&gt;G. H. Hardy&lt;/a&gt;, who was educated in Cambridge, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=9179&#34;&gt;Issai Schur&lt;/a&gt;, from Berlin. The Berlin side of my &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo; has a completely continental European background, while the Cambridge side is firmly English for generations, until you go back to the 17th Century, where you find that Isaac Newton&amp;rsquo;s grandparent &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=133302&#34;&gt;Vincenzo Viviani&lt;/a&gt; was educated at the University of Pisa (and one of his Doctoral advisors was &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=18231&#34;&gt;Galileo Galilei&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See if you can spot &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=125434&#34;&gt;Mersenne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=18231&#34;&gt;Gauss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=74313&#34;&gt;Newton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=18231&#34;&gt;Galileo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=7486&#34;&gt;Weierstrass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=7824&#34;&gt;Cayley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=4642&#34;&gt;Frobenius&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=125938&#34;&gt;Erasmus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=141571&#34;&gt;Cranmer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://genealogy.math.ndsu.nodak.edu/id.php?id=131539&#34;&gt;Ficino&lt;/a&gt; among my ancestors. It&amp;rsquo;s dizzying to see so much of your academic ancestry laid out for inspection, and to see how ideas have been passed down from generation to generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another striking thing about this genealogy? There are &lt;em&gt;no women there&lt;/em&gt;. None at all. (Not even among my own graduate students, each of whom I&amp;rsquo;m very proud indeed.) May this change, and change very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Richard, for &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucalgary.ca/rzach/blog/2015/02/academic-genealogy-graphed.html&#34;&gt;the prompt&lt;/a&gt;. This has been a delight to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Contingent Existence and Modal Definedness</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/cemd-anu/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/cemd-anu/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A seminar for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://philrsss.anu.edu.au/regular-seminars&#34;&gt;ANU School of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. I will discuss Tim Williamson&amp;rsquo;s arguments for the non-contingency of existence (see his &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780199552078.do&#34;&gt;Modal Logic as Metaphysics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, 2013) and explain how and why they might be reasonably resisted. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain the impact of proof theory for theories of meaning and for metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/handouts/cemd-preseminar-on-meaning-rules-and-defining-concepts.pdf&#34;&gt;Handout&lt;/a&gt; for the pre-seminar talk for graduate students, on &lt;em&gt;Meaning Rules and Defining Concepts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/handouts/cemd-anu-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;Handout&lt;/a&gt; for the seminar presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/slides/cemd-talk.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt; for the seminar presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Classes in Semester One</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/semester-one-classes/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:55:17 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/semester-one-classes/</guid>
<description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL30043/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Power_and_Limits.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Power and Limits of Logic&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Power and Limits of Logic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching started for first semester, with the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic1_coursera/&#34;&gt;Logic: Language and Information 1&lt;/a&gt; on Coursera. That&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun already, with over 17,000 enrolled. There&amp;rsquo;s something very exciting about being involved with a large number of students all around the world, choosing to work hard to learn logic for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m most excited, though, by the next run-through of &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;Kurt G&amp;ouml;del&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Hits&lt;/a&gt;, starting next week. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching the class entirely in a flipped mode, with students working through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/2015/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;lecture videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;before class&lt;/em&gt; each week, and working with me on a mix of simpler peer instruction questions to establish the basic understanding of core concepts,  and going on to more complex material and independent engagement with the material. We meet weekly in a two hour seminar (from 9 to 11am each Monday&amp;mdash;what a way to start the week!). With a group of between 25 and 30 students, this will be intense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ground to cover, from soundness and completeness Theorems, through compactness, cardinality L&amp;oslash;wenheim&amp;ndash;Skolem theorems, computability, to G&amp;ouml;del&amp;rsquo;s Theorems and L&amp;ouml;b&amp;rsquo;s Theorem. It&amp;rsquo;ll be quite a ride. This material &lt;em&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; available through Coursera, but I have made the videos &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2015/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;available for your use&lt;/a&gt; if you wish. (I only ask that you acknowledge that you got them from here if you make them publicly available in any medium.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Logic: Language and Information 1</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic1_coursera/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2015/logic1_coursera/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jen Davoren and I are running &lt;em&gt;Logic Language and Information 1&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; again in 2015. You can enrol &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/logic1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Ash Wednesday</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/ash-wednesday/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 11:59:50 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/ash-wednesday/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Rembember that you are dust, and to dust you shall return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/zPrjSnlQ-h/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Remember that you are dust (@consequently)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-02-18T13:57:17+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 18, 2015 at 5:57am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Do LNC and LEM suffice to define negation?</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/lnc-and-lem-but-not-negation/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 23:20:25 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/lnc-and-lem-but-not-negation/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; negation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One answer you find in the literature is that negation is the operator that makes each instance of the &lt;em&gt;Law of the Excluded Middle&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt;) and the &lt;em&gt;Law of Non-Contradiction&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt;) turn out to be &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt;. That is, every sentence of the form
\[
p\lor \neg p
\qquad
\neg(p\land\neg p)
\]
is true, no matter what sentence we use in the place of \(p\) (where \(\neg\) stands for negation, \(\lor\) for disjunction, and \(\land\) for conjunction).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; way to try to define negation. If you read on, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I explain why, though, I should explain that taking &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; as defining negation isn&amp;rsquo;t an idiosyncratic view. If you read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ling.yale.edu/people/laurence-r-horn&#34;&gt;Laurence Horn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/contradiction&#34;&gt;entry on Contradiction in the &lt;em&gt;Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and I recommend you do read it, it&amp;rsquo;s a great discussion!), you&amp;rsquo;ll see that he characterises negation in this way. &lt;a href=&#34;http://grahampriest.net/&#34;&gt;Graham Priest&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s chapter &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grahampriest.net/?ddownload=773&#34;&gt;Why Not? A Defence of a Dialethic Theory of Negation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; takes this form of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; to be central to defining what it is for one thing to be contradictory to another&amp;mdash;in terms of which Graham characterises negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to think that this form of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; defines negation: It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see (once you check) that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t define &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;. Altogether too many putative one-place connectives satisfy both &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose that \(\mathord\sim A\) is just always interpreted as &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt;, whatever \(A\) happens to be. Then it turns out (if disjunction is interpreted in the usual way) that \(p\lor\mathord\sim p\) is true (since its second disjunct is true) and so is \(\mathord\sim(p\land\mathord\sim p)\) since it has the form \(\mathord\sim A\). So, given this deviant &amp;ldquo;negations are always true&amp;rdquo; interpretation, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; are always satisfied&amp;mdash;by \(\sim\), which isn&amp;rsquo;t negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t the only way one could interpret a sentential operator so as to satisfy &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt;. For an even more deviant reading, let&amp;rsquo;s interpret \(\mathord\sim A\) as \(\neg A\lor q\) for any \(A\) and for some sentence \(q\). Then &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; for \(\sim\)-negation,
that is,
\[
p\lor (\neg p\lor q)
\qquad
\neg(p\land(\neg p \lor q))\lor q
\]
are themselves &lt;em&gt;logically true&lt;/em&gt; (I leave the verification of this is an exercise for you). But \(\mathord\sim A\)&amp;mdash;that is, \(\neg A\lor q\)&amp;mdash;really isn&amp;rsquo;t the negation of \(A\). (If we choose \(q\) to be a &lt;em&gt;tautology&lt;/em&gt; then \(\mathord\sim A\) is simply equivalent to \(\top\) which is the interpretation we saw before.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if all we have to go on for interpreting &amp;ldquo;\(\sim\)&amp;rdquo; is that it satisfies  &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt;, then there many different ways it can be interpreted, including taking it to be highly contingent, where the semantic value of \(\mathord\sim A\) depends on more than just the semantic value of \(A\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EXCURSUS&lt;/span&gt;: If you&amp;rsquo;re prepared to go further afield, notice that in reflexive classical modal logics, we have both \(p\lor\Diamond\neg p\) and \(\Diamond\neg(p\land\Diamond\neg p)\) so satisfying &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to tell us that we don&amp;rsquo;t mean &amp;ldquo;possibly not&amp;rdquo; by your so-called &amp;ldquo;negation&amp;rdquo;. And instead of \(\Diamond\neg\) you could use \(\Diamond\Diamond\neg\) or \(\Diamond\Diamond\Diamond\neg\)&amp;hellip; etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a similar point in the context of first-order predicate logic, choose \(x\) to be a variable at random, and read \(\mathord\sim A\) as \((\exists x)\neg A\), whether \(x\) is free in the formula \(A\) &lt;em&gt;or not&lt;/em&gt;. Notice that this very strange variable-binding &amp;ldquo;negation&amp;rdquo; still satisfies &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt;, since \(A\lor (\exists x)\neg A\) and \((\exists x)\neg (A\land (\exists x)\neg A)\) are tautologies, but \((\exists x)\neg\) is not &lt;em&gt;negation&lt;/em&gt;. This bizarre creature binds a variable. Negation, as we traditionally understand it, doesn&amp;rsquo;t.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; in the traditional form don&amp;rsquo;t do enough by themselves to pin down negation, what can we say? Something I&amp;rsquo;ve argued &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/lnclem/&#34;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is that the right way to understand &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; is more like this:
\[
\vdash p\lor \neg p
\qquad
p\land\neg p\vdash
\]
&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; (\(\vdash p\lor \neg p\)) tells us that \(p\lor\neg p\) is &lt;em&gt;undeniable&lt;/em&gt; (to &lt;em&gt;deny&lt;/em&gt; it is &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/multipleconclusions&#34;&gt;out of bounds&lt;/a&gt;), and this &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; (\(p\land\neg p\vdash\)) tells us that \(p\land\neg p\) is &lt;em&gt;unassertable&lt;/em&gt; (to &lt;em&gt;assert&lt;/em&gt; it is &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/multipleconclusions&#34;&gt;out of bounds&lt;/a&gt;). This pair of rules does a &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better job of pinning down the behaviour of negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just how much better? Well, given a little more logic (the traditional sequent calculus rules for \(\land\) and \(\lor\), and the &lt;em&gt;Cut&lt;/em&gt; rule), then if \(\neg\) and \(\sim\) both satisfy &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; in this form, then both negations are logically equivalent. Here&amp;rsquo;s a demonstration that \(\mathord\sim A\vdash\neg A\) (you can generalise this to a proof of equivalence, though the dual proof of \(\neg A\vdash\mathord\sim A\)). Since \(A\land\mathord\sim A\vdash\), by the usual behaviour of \(\land\), we have \(A,\mathord\sim A\vdash\). Since \(\vdash A\lor\neg A\), by the usual behaviour of \(\lor\), we have \(\vdash A,\neg A\). From \(\vdash A,\neg A\) and \(A,\mathord\sim A\vdash\), by the &lt;em&gt;Cut&lt;/em&gt; rule (cutting on \(A\)) we have \(\mathord\sim A\vdash\neg A\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are tempted by the idea that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; together &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; negation, you should be careful to specify &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;denial&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;rejection&lt;/em&gt; rule (\(p\land\neg p\vdash\), which says that \(p\land\neg p\) is to be denied, or to be rejected), rather than \(\neg(p\land \neg p)\) which isn&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to say what you want it to say&amp;mdash;the &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; instances of negation gives you altogether too much wiggle room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this is an argument that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LNC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LEM&lt;/span&gt; actually &lt;em&gt;hold&lt;/em&gt;. For that, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to look elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Adding Site Search</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/adding-site-search/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 11:19:07 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/adding-site-search/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added a search feature to the site in the &lt;a href=&#34;#footer&#34;&gt;footer&lt;/a&gt; of each page. There seems to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news&#34;&gt;enough on the site&lt;/a&gt; that search is genuinely useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;a href=&#34;http://duckduckgo.com&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;, which has a comprehensive index of this place, and which &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/params&#34;&gt;can be styled&lt;/a&gt; to match the visual treatment of the rest of the site. Please &lt;a href=&#34;#contact&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; if there are any problems with the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Another Blast From the Past</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/another-blast-from-the-past/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 15:02:19 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/another-blast-from-the-past/</guid>
<description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://pluralism.pitas.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/LPWL@pitas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Logical Pluralism | Work Log&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A blast from the past&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2015/recovering-the-past/&#34;&gt;recovering the archives for this site&lt;/a&gt;, I came across another blast from the past: the &lt;a href=&#34;http://pluralism.pitas.com&#34;&gt;weblog I ran&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://entailments.net&#34;&gt;Jc&lt;/a&gt; during the early days of our research on logical pluralism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pluralism.pitas.com&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a weblog&lt;/a&gt; that we ran from to October 1999 to September 2001, with things we found related to logical pluralism, notes from our research, and details of talks and various other bits and pieces along the way. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the nuances of logical pluralism, there&amp;rsquo;s lots of material there, some of which didn&amp;rsquo;t make it into &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/pluralism/&#34;&gt;our book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that in an age where many other free online services shut up shop and disappeared, the platform &amp;ldquo;pitas&amp;rdquo; is still faithfully serving up those pages. It launched in 1999, along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://diaryland.com&#34;&gt;Diaryland&lt;/a&gt;, which is still going strong after all of these years. (Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@maryps/a-conversation-with-andrew-smales-founder-of-diaryland-15e3d1ffc7dc&#34;&gt;the story of Andrew Smales, the founder, here&lt;/a&gt; for the backstory.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might also be worth noting that back in the late 1990s and early 2000s, I also favoured a simple &amp;ldquo;black and white with red highlights&amp;rdquo; colour scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Recovering the Past</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/recovering-the-past/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 07:20:10 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/recovering-the-past/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you glance at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news&#34;&gt;news archive&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that once again it stretches back to the dim past of weblog days, &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/#2000&#34;&gt;the year 2000&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20000815223330/http://www.phil.mq.edu.au/staff/grestall/log/&#34;&gt;wayback machine&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to recover entries from my old blog (powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogger.com&#34;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt;, from well before it was acquired by Google), and fulfil a commitment I made in March 2001 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2001/2001_03_01_archive/&#34;&gt;move the old archives over to consequently.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the old news archives were &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20030630084127/http://consequently.org/news/archives.html&#34;&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; for a little while here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org&#34;&gt;consequently.org&lt;/a&gt;, but once those entries disappeared from the server at Macquarie University, I dropped the links from the server. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered the articles, they&amp;rsquo;re back in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/#2000&#34;&gt;news archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entries from &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2002/2002_03&#34;&gt;March 2002&lt;/a&gt; and earlier had no titles. This was an artefact of how Blogger was set up in the early years, before we used RSS feeds with titles to distribute blog entries. So, importing them into an archive where entries all &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have titles forced a choice. I took the easy way out, and decided that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2000/2000_03_01_archive&#34;&gt;month&amp;rsquo;s worth of entries&lt;/a&gt; was an &amp;lsquo;entry&amp;rsquo; in the new regime, with the title &amp;lsquo;News from &lt;em&gt;Month X&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rsquo; They&amp;rsquo;re all there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can browse through my early days of online writing, where the entries skip between &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2001/2001_06/#12&#34;&gt;short observations&lt;/a&gt; that now belong on twitter (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/speedysnail&#34;&gt;hi Rory!&lt;/a&gt;) to &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news/2001/2001_06/#13&#34;&gt;personal tales of life as a young father&lt;/a&gt; in short order, and the archive is relatively complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I thank the hardworking people at &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.org&#34;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt; who archive and index the history of the web. It&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure (with its mixture of delight and embarrassment) to recover this history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Back in the office</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/back-in-the-office/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 12:45:04 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/back-in-the-office/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to be back in the office. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.unimelb.edu.au/parkville&#34;&gt;Parkville Campus&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au/&#34;&gt;The University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; is a delightful place to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/ylDNTZlQ7L/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;It’s February, and I’m back in the office.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Greg Restall (@consequently) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-02-02T00:36:39+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 1, 2015 at 4:36pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you climbed into that open window in the picture, you&amp;rsquo;d be in my office. I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend trying that way into the building&amp;mdash;navigating the corridors and stairs, though tricky, is much safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/consequently&#34;&gt;posting pictures on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; these days. I&amp;rsquo;ll include some here, but more are there, if you want to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Why no comment box?</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/no-comments/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 09:52:39 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/no-comments/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Previous incarnations of this website provided a facility for comments in the usual way for a weblog in the first decade of the 2000s&amp;mdash;a comment form on each entry. This one doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Comment forms are ugly. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend time &lt;em&gt;moderating comments&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;wading through yet another medium that&amp;rsquo;s 90% spam is  not a good way for me to use my time or energy. Publically available comment forms on the web are mostly buckets for spam and other detritus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, there are &lt;em&gt;plenty of other ways&lt;/em&gt; you can comment on anything I do here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best way is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/consequently&#34;&gt;reply to me on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Use your favourite twitter client and post a link to news item you&amp;rsquo;re discussing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you include the reference to my twitter handle &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/consequently&#34;&gt;@consequently&lt;/a&gt;,  or if you simply link to a page on this site, I&amp;rsquo;ll see your reply when I check twitter. It&amp;rsquo;s really easy for me to include tweets in posts, like this one &amp;hellip; &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All-star logic workshop in Banff, 2007 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TT?src=hash&#34;&gt;#TT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/0qBKXxfyyl&#34;&gt;http://t.co/0qBKXxfyyl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/yMX8yHufgn&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/yMX8yHufgn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Richard Zach (@RrrichardZach) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RrrichardZach/status/558299627569836032&#34;&gt;January 22, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &amp;hellip; so if you&amp;rsquo;d like to comment, that&amp;rsquo;s a great way to get a short message out, in public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, if you&amp;rsquo;ve got something that&amp;rsquo;s longer than a tweet&amp;rsquo;s worth, write it, make it available on the web, and let me know. If I get useful feedback in public, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to link to it on the page, or point readers to it on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or you could always just &lt;a href=&#34;#about&#34;&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>What’s the point of a personal website these days?</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/news/2015/the-point/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 23:05:00 AEDT</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/news/2015/the-point/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My last post to &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org&#34;&gt;consequently.org&lt;/a&gt; was in late in 2010, well over four years ago. You&amp;rsquo;d be &lt;em&gt;justified&lt;/em&gt; in thinking that I&amp;rsquo;d abandoned the place&amp;mdash;but you&amp;rsquo;d also be &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with it behind the scenes. The software I&amp;rsquo;d been using to maintain the website has long since &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TwP/webby&#34;&gt;fallen into disrepair&lt;/a&gt;, so updating it meant porting everything to another content management system. At least, it would have to mean that, given that I &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; really keen to burn the whole thing to the ground and start again from scratch. This required &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t require &lt;em&gt;four years&lt;/em&gt;, but it did require an uninterrupted stretch of time to tinker with software, experiment with the design, and finally, piece everything back together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before getting back into all of this website business, however, I wanted to answer one question. Is the investment of time worth it? &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the point of a personal website these days, anyway&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, people can &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/consequently&#34;&gt;find me on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, where you might find a brief remark or more each week. (Or you might find a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?f=realtime&amp;amp;q=%23advent%20OR%20%23adventure%20OR%20%23christmas%20from%3Aconsequently%20since%3A2014-11-30%20until%3A2014-12-27&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;virtual “advent calendar”&lt;/a&gt; when I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a bit more adventurous.) I occasionally &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/consequently&#34;&gt;post photos on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, so you can see me there if you like that sort of thing. You can find (most of) &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=LfBBS7AAAAAJ&#34;&gt;my publications on Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;, and you can even find &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/consequently/&#34;&gt;instructional videos I&amp;rsquo;ve made available to the public on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. You can even join in with &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org/course/logic1&#34;&gt;classes I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org/course/logic2&#34;&gt;teach (with Jen Davoren) on Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, and you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://philevents.org&#34;&gt;philevents.org&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://philevents.org/search/index/searchForm?span=PAST&amp;amp;customTag=&amp;amp;speakers%5B0%5D.id=1176&amp;amp;autonamespeaker=Greg+Restall&amp;amp;series=&amp;amp;search=true&amp;amp;hits=&amp;amp;widget=&amp;amp;Search=Search&#34;&gt;keep track of talks I&amp;rsquo;ve given&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;ve  been inactive on the web, even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t been leaving a much of a trace &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt; lately. Isn&amp;rsquo;t all that web presence enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it isn&amp;rsquo;t. At least, it isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for me in 2015. Let me explain why, by turning to the different sections of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; section keeps track of all of my academic publications. Where I can, I archive pre- or post-publication versions of my papers, and sometimes I upload versions of papers here &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; submission, to get the ideas out as quickly as possible, and to get feedback. I could do that without having my own website. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://philpapers.org&#34;&gt;Philpapers.org&lt;/a&gt; is a great way for people to upload draft papers in philosophy, for example.) But at your &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; site, you can present yourself however you see fit, and you can make it easy for people to find your work. You provide a &lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt; for  aggregators to aggregate. That&amp;rsquo;s one reason to take control of your own body of work. As long as the &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; protocol keeps going, I can host my own work and people can find it. &lt;em&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;philpapers&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;journal websites&lt;/em&gt; can come or go. As long as people can get here, they can keep track of my work. If someone asks how to keep up with what I write, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;ll point them. A &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; I control: &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing&#34;&gt;http://consequently.org/writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class&#34;&gt;Classes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; sections of the website were more pressing for me, though, as I thought about why it was important to have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebooks.adelaide.edu.au/w/woolf/virginia/w91r/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;room of one&amp;rsquo;s own&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the web. I&amp;rsquo;ve been making more of my &lt;em&gt;teaching&lt;/em&gt; resources available to the public, through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/gregrestall&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; and using &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/consequently/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. While I use our campus &lt;a href=&#34;https://lms.unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;LMS&lt;/a&gt; to distribute materials to my on-campus students, that&amp;rsquo;s basically walled off to non-students. I can&amp;rsquo;t point non-Melbourne students to that if I want to give them access to teaching resources, or simply to catch up on what I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have somewhere to do that. So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class&#34;&gt;http://consequently.org/class&lt;/a&gt; will serve as a directory of all my recent and future teaching resources—at least, all of the resources I&amp;rsquo;ll be making freely available to everyone, and it can be a straightforward first port-of-call for anyone who wants to check out a class I teach, to see if it interests them. Teaching is a very important part of what I do, and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to spread this material far and wide if it will help others. I think it will help me, too: the more opportunities for feedback on teaching materials I get, the better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation&#34;&gt;Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The same holds for &lt;em&gt;talks&lt;/em&gt; I give. I&amp;rsquo;d like there to be a simple, stable URL for each talk, whether it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/towards-fixed-point-models-logicmelb/&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/trmra-asubl5/&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation/2015/cemd-anu/&#34;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/christian-academic-monash/&#34;&gt;different&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/tractatus-masterclass/&#34;&gt;kind of presentation&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll put materials from talks online, and sometimes I won&amp;rsquo;t. But in any case, I want to have an archive of recent and upcoming talks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the &lt;em&gt;news&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; section of the website, which can be the home for not-academic pieces of writing which don&amp;rsquo;t fit well into &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/consequently&#34;&gt;140 character&lt;/a&gt; chunks, and which don&amp;rsquo;t find a place in &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing&#34;&gt;more considered pieces&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; These are pieces of writing like &lt;em&gt;this very discussion&lt;/em&gt;. While some find places like &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; a suitable home for longer-than-twitter online writing, I&amp;rsquo;m fond of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/catarinadutilhnovaes/&#34;&gt;people&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umsu.de/wo/&#34;&gt;own&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://kjhealy.org&#34;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m itching to get back into it, with some occasional writing of my own, to supplement more considered academic pieces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of my return to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s end with the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. The short answer is what you see in the footer of the website (as I write this). &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is the CMS that wires things together into the website. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, relatively straightforward to learn if you&amp;rsquo;re used to command-line tools, and can it cope with the not-completely-straightforward taxonomy of my site. Hugo seems to be under active development by its founder &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/spf13/&#34;&gt;Steve Francia&lt;/a&gt; together with an active &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; of users and developers. It looks like it&amp;rsquo;ll be around for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hand-coded the HTML (designing it to be &lt;em&gt;relatively&lt;/em&gt; friendly for small-screen devices) using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://imperavi.com/kube/&#34;&gt;Kube Web Framework&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://imperavi.com&#34;&gt;Imperavi&lt;/a&gt;. (Please let me know if you see any website design bugs.) The main body and header font is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Alegreya&#34;&gt;Alegreya&lt;/a&gt;, a gorgeous font designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/juandelperal&#34;&gt;Juan Pablo del Peral&lt;/a&gt; for the Argentinian Type Foundry &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huertatipografica.com&#34;&gt;Huerta Tipogr&amp;aacute;fica&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Alegreya&#34;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/a&gt;. Apply liberal doses of &lt;a href=&#34;http://marketlane.com.au&#34;&gt;caffeine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cockburnproject.net&#34;&gt;Bruce Cockburn&lt;/a&gt;, a few late nights&amp;rsquo; worth of coding, and you get the website you have before you. I hope you like it. Please get back to me, by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/consequently&#34;&gt;replying to @consequently&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, or by email, if you have any feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Ternary Relations and Models for Relevant Arithmetics</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/trmra-asubl5/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/trmra-asubl5/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A seminar at the workshop &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/a/ltumathstats.com/asubl5&#34;&gt;Algebra and Substructural Logic 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (La Trobe, December 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain how the `trace model&amp;rsquo; for relevant arithmetic (introduced &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/mfsa/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) can be extended quite naturally to model a logic including a de Morgan negation. The result is not a model for the logic &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;, but for its weaker cousin, &lt;strong&gt;TW&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Normal Proofs, Cut Free Derivations and Structural Rules</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/npcfdsr/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/npcfdsr/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Different natural deduction proof systems for intuitionistic and classical logic&amp;mdash;and related logical systems&amp;mdash;differ in fundamental properties while sharing significant family resemblances. These differences become quite stark when it comes to the structural rules of contraction and weakening. In this paper, I show how Gentzen and Jas&amp;#x301;kowski&amp;rsquo;s natural deduction systems differ in fine structure. I also motivate directed proof nets as another natural deduction system which shares some of the design features of Genzen and Jas&amp;#x301;kowski&amp;rsquo;s systems, but which differs again in its treatment of the structural rules, and has a range of virtues absent from traditional natural deduction systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Living as a Christian Academic</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/christian-academic-monash/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/christian-academic-monash/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a presentation to postgraduate students in the Monash University Christian Union about life as a Christian academic, and my journey from being an undergraduate in Mathematics at the University of Queensland in the late 1980s, to my current role as Professor of Philosophy at the University of Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Towards Fixed Point Models for Theories of Properties and Classes</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/towards-fixed-point-models-logicmelb/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/towards-fixed-point-models-logicmelb/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A seminar at the University of Melbourne Logic Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketch some of the features of models of na&amp;iuml;ve theories of properties or classes defined by finding a space C that is isomorphic to the class of continuous functions [C &amp;cup; D &amp;rarr; &amp;Omega;].&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Ludwig Wittgenstein&amp;rsquo;s Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/tractatus-masterclass/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/tractatus-masterclass/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a masterclass on Ludwig Wittegenstein&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus&lt;/em&gt; in the University of Melbourne&amp;rsquo;s 10 Great Books Masterclass in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Pluralism and Proofs</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/pluralism-and-proofs/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/pluralism-and-proofs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Beall and Restall&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Logical Pluralism&lt;/em&gt; (2006) characterises pluralism about logical consequence in terms of the different ways cases can be selected in the analysis of logical consequence as preservation of truth over a class of cases. This is not the only way to understand or to motivate pluralism about logical consequence. Here, I will examine pluralism about logical consequence in terms of different standards of proof. We will focus on sequent derivations for classical logic, imposing two different restrictions on classical derivations to produce derivations focusr intuitionistic logic and for dual intuitionistic logic. The result is another way to understand the manner in which we can have different consequence relations in the same language. Furthermore, the proof-theoretic perspective gives us a different explanation of how the one concept of negation can have three different truth conditions, those in classical, intuitionistic and dual-intuitionistic models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL30043: The Power and Limits of Logic</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL30043/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL30043/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHIL30043: The Power and Limits of Logic&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate subject. It covers the metatheory of classical first order predicate logic, beginning at the &lt;em&gt;Soundness&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Completeness&lt;/em&gt; Theorems (proved not once but &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt;, first for a tableaux proof system for predicate logic, then a Hilbert proof system), through the &lt;em&gt;Deduction Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Compactness&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cantor&amp;rsquo;s Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Downward L&amp;ouml;wenheim&amp;ndash;Skolem Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Recursive Functions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Register Machines&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Representability&lt;/em&gt; and ending up at &lt;em&gt;G&amp;ouml;del&amp;rsquo;s Incompleteness Theorems&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;L&amp;ouml;b&amp;rsquo;s Theorem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject was taught to University of Melbourne undergraduate students (for Arts students as a part of the Philosophy major, for non-Arts students, as a breadth subject). Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2014/PHIL30043&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I made use of video lectures I have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2262409&#34;&gt;freely available on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL10003: Philosophy, the Great Thinkers</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL10003/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL10003/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHIL10003: Philosophy, the Great Thinkers&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate subject, introducing philosophy to students through close readings of core texts. I taught with Dr. Chris Cordner and Dr. Ruth Boeker. In my classes, we looked at David Hume&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhume.org/texts/dnr.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dialogues Concerning Natural Religion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebooks.adelaide.edu.au/h/hume/david/h92n/contents.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natural History of Religion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with some side trips into hume&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhume.org/texts/ehu.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enquiry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and some Marx, Wittgenstein for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject was taught to University of Melbourne undergraduate students (for Arts students as a part of the Philosophy major, for non-Arts students, as a breadth subject). Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2014/PHIL10003&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>From Defining Rules to Cut Elimination (and its consequences)</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/from-defining-rules-nip-mfl/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/from-defining-rules-nip-mfl/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A presentation at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abdn.ac.uk/nip/events/event?id=476&#34;&gt;Metaphysical Basis of Logic Workshop&lt;/a&gt; at the Northern Institute of Philosophy, University of Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Proof Theory and Philosophy</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PTP-NIP/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PTP-NIP/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I taught an intensive class on proof theory and its applications to Philosophy at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abdn.ac.uk/nip/events/event?id=474&#34;&gt;NIP Summer School on the Foundations of Logic and Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;, June&amp;nbsp;July 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Modal Definedness</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/modal-definedness-arche/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/modal-definedness-arche/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A presentation in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/arche/events/event?id=811&#34;&gt;workshop in the Philosophy of Logic&lt;/a&gt; at Arch&amp;eacute;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distinction between &lt;i&gt;defined&lt;/i&gt; terms and &lt;i&gt;undefined&lt;/i&gt; terms provides a metaphysically &amp;ldquo;light&amp;rdquo; way to give a semantics for free logic. Singular terms may be undefined, and if they are undefined, they are not appropriate substitution instances for inference rules for the quantifiers. Sol Feferman, in &amp;ldquo;Definedness&amp;rdquo; (&lt;i&gt;Erkenntnis&lt;/i&gt;, 1995), provides an elegant system for an extensional negative free logic with undefined terms: it is a very natural model for mathematical reasoning in which we allow undefined terms (like &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;) and we keep track of the behaviour of such terms by talking of when they are defined and when they are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free logics also see use when it comes to quantified modal logic. It is very tempting to conceive of the domain of quantification as varying from world to world, that what exists in one world might fail to exist in another. This seems to be a very different motivation for free logics—terms which denote in this world and which do not denote in another are not &lt;i&gt;undefined&lt;/i&gt; at that world. They are defined all too well—defined to denote something that fails to exist at that world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will explain the motivations for these two different approaches to free logic, and show that a sequent calculus for Feferman&amp;rsquo;s own system (with a metaphysically &amp;lsquo;light&amp;rsquo; interpretation, that eschews all talk of an outer domain of quantification of non-existent objects) can, with one small change, be naturally extended into a modal hypersequent calculus for a quantified modal logic with a non-constant domain. This, too, has a metaphysically &amp;lsquo;light&amp;rsquo; interpretation.  The result is a natural proof-theoretical account of a modal logic with varying domain, in which the Barcan formula not only fails, but fails straightforwardly, in a well motivated way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After introducing the modal system, I will consider what this might mean, about the nature of quantification, and the role of defining rules in characterising logical constants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Ternary Relations and Models for Relevant Arithmetics</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/trmra-logicmelb/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/presentation/2014/trmra-logicmelb/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A seminar at &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://philevents.org/event/show/14562&#34;&gt;Melbourne Logic Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, May 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain how the &amp;lsquo;trace model&amp;rsquo; for relevant arithmetic (introduced &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/mfsa/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) can be extended quite naturally to model a logic including a de Morgan negation. The result is not a model for the logic &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;, but for its weaker cousin, &lt;strong&gt;TW&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Logic: Language and Information 2</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic2_coursera/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic2_coursera/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jen Davoren and I taught &lt;em&gt;Logic Language and Information 2&lt;/em&gt; (an introduction to predicate logic and its applications) through &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; for the first time in 2014. An archive of the material is available  &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>UNIB10002: Logic, Language and Information</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/UNIB10002/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/UNIB10002/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNIB10002: Logic, Language and Information&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate breadth subject, introducing logic and its applications to students from a broad range of disciplines in the Arts, Sciences and Engineering. I coordinate this subject with my colleague Dr. Jen Davoren, with help from Dr. Lesley Stirling and Dr. Peter Schachte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject was taught to University of Melbourne undergraduate students. Details for enrolment are &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2014/UNIB10002&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We teach this in a &amp;lsquo;flipped classroom&amp;rsquo; model, using resources from our Coursera subjects &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic1_coursera&#34;&gt;Logic 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic2_coursera&#34;&gt;Logic 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL40007: Philosophy of Language and Mind</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL40007/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL40007/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHIL40007: Philosophy of Language and Mind&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; honours seminar subject for fourth-year students. Our aim in the Honours program is to introduce students to current work in research in Philosophy. In 2014, I introduced the students to the normative pragmatism and inferentialism of Robert Brandom, through a close reading of his book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Articulating-Reasons-An-Introduction-Inferentialism/dp/0674006925/consequentlyorg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Articulating Reasons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and related literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>PHIL20030: Meaning, Possibility and Paradox</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL20030/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/PHIL20030/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHIL20030: Meaning, Possibility and Paradox&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unimelb.edu.au&#34;&gt;University of Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; undergraduate subject. The idea that the meaning of a sentence depends on the meanings of its parts is fundamental to the way we understand logic, language and the mind. In this subject, we looked at the different ways that this idea has been applied in logic throughout the 20th Century and into the present day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the subject, our focus is on the concepts of necessity and possibility, and the way that &amp;lsquo;possible worlds semantics&amp;rsquo; has been used in theories of meaning. We will focus on the logic of necessity and possibility (modal logic), times (temporal logic), conditionality and dependence (counterfactuals), and the notions of analyticity and a priority so important to much of philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the subject, we examined closely the assumption that every statement we make is either true or false but not both. We will examine the paradoxes of truth (like the so-called &amp;lsquo;liar paradox&amp;rsquo;) and vagueness (the ‘sorites paradox&amp;rsquo;), and we will investigate different ways attempts at resolving these paradoxes by going beyond our traditional views of truth (using &amp;lsquo;many valued logics&amp;rsquo;) or by defending the traditional perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject serves as an introduction to ways that logic is applied in the study of language, epistemology and metaphysics, so it is useful to those who already know some philosophy and would like to see how logic relates to those issues. It is also useful to those who already know some logic and would like to learn new logical techniques and see how these techniques can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Dr Rohan French taught the bulk of this subject, using materials that he and I developed. We made use of video lectures I have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/2470375&#34;&gt;freely available on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>MULT10016: Reason</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/MULT10016/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/MULT10016/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I participated in the Arts Foundation subject &lt;a href=&#34;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/view/2014/MULT10016&#34;&gt;MULT10016: Reason&lt;/a&gt;. I taught six classes, on Plato, Aristotle and Hume.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Logic: Language and Information 1</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic1_coursera/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/class/2014/logic1_coursera/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jen Davoren and I taught &lt;em&gt;Logic Language and Information 1&lt;/em&gt; (an introduction to propositional logic and its applications) through &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.org&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; for the first time in 2014. An archive of the material is available  &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Assertion, Denial and Non-Classical Theories</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/adnct/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/adnct/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper I urge friends of truth-value gaps and truth-value gluts &amp;ndash; proponents of paracomplete and paraconsistent logics &amp;ndash; to consider theories not merely as sets of sentences, but as &lt;em&gt;pairs&lt;/em&gt; of sets of sentences, or what I call &amp;lsquo;bitheories,&amp;rsquo; which keep track not only of what &lt;em&gt;holds&lt;/em&gt; according to the theory, but also what &lt;em&gt;fails&lt;/em&gt; to hold according to the theory.  I explain the connection between bitheories, sequents, and the speech acts of assertion and denial. I illustrate the usefulness of bitheories by showing how they make available a technique for characterising different theories while abstracting away from logical vocabulary such as connectives or quantifiers, thereby making theoretical commitments independent of the choice of this or that particular non-classical logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples discussed include theories of numbers, classes and truth.  In the latter two cases, the bitheoretical perspective brings to light some heretofore unconsidered puzzles for friends of na&amp;iuml;ve theories of classes and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Special Issue of the Logic Journal of the IGPL: Non-Classical Mathematics</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/ncm-igpl-2013/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/ncm-igpl-2013/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A special issue of the Logic Journal of the IGPL, on Non-Classical Mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editorial Preface&lt;/em&gt;, Libor B&amp;#x115;hounek, Greg Restall, and Giovanni Sambin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Mathematical pluralism,&amp;quot; Graham Priest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;A first constructive look at the comparison of projections,&amp;quot; Douglas S. Bridges and Lumini&amp;#x163;a S. V&amp;icirc;&amp;#x163;a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Lipschitz functions in constructive reverse mathematics,&amp;quot; Iris Loeb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Constructive version of Boolean algebra,&amp;quot; Francesco Ciraulo, Maria Emilia Maietti, and Paola Toto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;A generalized cut characterization of the fullness axiom in CZF,&amp;quot; Laura Crosilla, Erik Palmgren, and Peter Schuster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Interpreting lattice-valued set theory in fuzzy set theory,&amp;quot; Petr H&amp;aacute;jek and Zuzana Hanikov&amp;aacute;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;On equality and natural numbers in Cantor-&amp;#x141;ukasiewicz set theory,&amp;quot; Petr H&amp;aacute;jek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Identity taken seriously: a non-classical approach,&amp;quot; Chris Mortensen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Strong, universal and provably non-trivial set theory by means of adaptive logic,&amp;quot; Peter Verdee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire issue can be &lt;a href=&#34;http://jigpal.oxfordjournals.org/content/21/1.toc&#34;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>New Waves in Philosophical Logic</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/new-waves-in-philosophical-logic/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/new-waves-in-philosophical-logic/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Philosophical logic has been, and continues to be, a driving force behind much progress and development in philosophy more broadly. This collection of 12 original papers by 15 up-and-coming philosophical logicians deals with a broad range of topics, including proof-theory, probability, context-sensitivity, dialetheism and dynamic semantics. If the discipline&amp;rsquo;s past influence on the core areas of philosophy is anything to go by, then the scholars and the ideas in these pages are the ones to watch. Here are the essays in the volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/papers/NewWavesIntroduction.pdf&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;, Greg Restall and Gillian Russell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Things Are Elsewhere, Wolfgang Schwarz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Change and First-Order Dynamic Logic, Barteld Kooi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://consequently.org/writing/interp-apply-ptml&#34;&gt;Interpreting and Applying Proof Theories for Modal Logic&lt;/a&gt;, Francesca Poggiolesi and Greg Restall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Logic(s) of Modal Knowledge, Daniel Cohnitz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Type-Free Truth to Type-Free Probability, Hannes Leitgeb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dogmatism, Probability and Logical Uncertainty, David Jehle and Brian Weatherson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skepticism about Reasoning, Sherrilyn Roush, Kelty Allen and Ian Herbert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons in Philosophy of Logic from Medieval Obligationes, Catarina Dutilh Novaes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Rule Out Things with Words:Strong Paraconsistency and the Algebra of Exclusion, Francesco Berto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons from the Logic of Demonstratives, Gillian Russell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Multitude View on Logic, Matti Eklund&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>A Cut-Free Sequent System for Two-Dimensional Modal Logic, and why it matters</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/cfss2dml/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/cfss2dml/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The two-dimensional modal logic of Davies and Humberstone is an important aid to our understanding the relationship between actuality, necessity and a priori knowability. I show how a cut-free hypersequent calculus for 2d modal logic not only captures the logic precisely, but may be used to address issues in the epistemology and metaphysics of our modal concepts. I will explain how use of our concepts motivates the inference rules of the sequent calculus, and then show that the completeness of the calculus for Davies&amp;ndash;Humberstone models explains why those concepts have the structure described by those models. The result is yet another application of the completeness theorem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This paper was awarded a Silver Medal for the Kurt Go&amp;#x308;del Prize in 2011.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Bradwardine Hypersequents</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/bradwardine-hypersequents/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/bradwardine-hypersequents/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;According to Stephen Read, Thomas Bradwardine&amp;rsquo;s theory of truth provides an independently motivated solution to the paradoxes of truth, such as the liar. In a series of papers, I have discussed modal models for Read&amp;rsquo;s reconstruction of Bradwardine&amp;rsquo;s theory. In this paper, provide a hypersequent calculus for this theory, and I show that the cut rule is admissible in the hypersequent calculus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This paper is dedicated to Professor Stephen Read, whose work has been a profound influence on my own. His work on relevant logic, on proof theoretical harmony, on the logic of identity and on Thomas Brad- wardine&amp;rsquo;s theory of truth have been a rich source of insight, of stimulation and of provocation. In an attempt to both honour Stephen, and hopefully to give him some pleasure, I am going to attempt to cook up something original using some of the many and varied ingredients he has provided us. In this paper, I will mix and match ideas and techniques from Stephen&amp;rsquo;s papers on proof theory, on Bradwardine&amp;rsquo;s theory of truth, and on identity to offer a harmonious sequent system for a theory of truth inspired by Stephen Read&amp;rsquo;s recovery of the work of Thomas Bradwardine.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Interpreting and Applying Proof Theories for Modal Logics</title>
<link>http://consequently.org/writing/interp-apply-ptml/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>http://consequently.org/writing/interp-apply-ptml/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Proof theory for modal logic has blossomed over recent years. Many ex- tensions of the classical sequent calculus have been proposed in order to give natural and appealing accounts of proof in modal logics like K, T, S4, S5, provability logics, and other modal systems. The common feature of each of these different proof systems consists in the general structure of the rules for modal operators. They provide introduction and elimination rules for statements of the form  &amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A (and &amp;#x25C7;&amp;#x10FC06;A), which show how those statements can feature as conclusions or as premises in deduction. These rules give an account of the deductive power of a modal formula 􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A (and 􏰆&amp;#x25C7;&amp;#x10FC06;A) in terms of the constituent formula A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distinctive feature for the modal operators in contemporary proof systems for modal logics is that the step introducing or eliminating 􏰅􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A is at the cost of introducing or eliminating some kind of extra structure in the proof. In this way, the proof rules for modal concepts such as 􏰅􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05; run in parallel with the truth conditions for these concepts in a Kripke model, in which the truth of 􏰅􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A stands or falls with the truth of A, but at the cost of checking that truth elsewhere, at points in the model accessible from the point at which 􏰅􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A is evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper we will introduce these recent advances in proof theory for a general audience, and then we will show how they are connected  with different—metaphysical and epistemic—conceptions of modality. We will show that these different pictures are nothing but different ways of connecting the statement 􏰅􏰅&amp;#x25A1;&amp;#x10FC05;A with the statement A, of showing the significance of modalising. In the light of this result we will draw conclusions about the link between analyticity and modality, and about the nature of a proof system for modal logics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
